A Guide to the Additional Papers of the Randolph Family of Edgehill 1784-1910 (1975)
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Dickins Family Papers
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1905; n.d. (Box-folder 3:12)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1906 March-August (Box-folder 3:13)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1906 September -October (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1906 November-December (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1907 January-June (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1907 July-August (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1907 October-December (Box-folder 3:18)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1908 January-February (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1908 March-June (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1908 July-August (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1908 September - December (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1909 January - March (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1909 June (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1909 September - December (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Harriot Dickins Wight to Theodora Keim 1910 (Box-folder 4:8)
- Series III: Documents of Thomas Jefferson, James Monroe, and Andrew Jackson
  - Ship's paper signed by Andrew Jackson n.d.
  - Richard Bayard to General Samuel Smith, U.S. Senate 1830 March 29 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Civil War related materials [1864] (Box-folder 5:2)
    Chiefly post-war news clippings; typescript of a speech[?] titled "Hot times between the lines" by J.B. Sinclair that describes an 1864 Union raid in Coventry, Va.; and, undated manuscript notes concerning General W.H. Payne's activities during 1864 in the Valley.
  - Robert Dinwiddie and Rebecca Dinwiddie signatures n.d. (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Thomas Jefferson Coat of Arms pamphlet n.d. (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Thomas Jefferson legal and financial papers 1777-1968 (Box-folder 5:5)
    Photocopies. Originals in Thomas Jefferson papers.
  - Thomas Jefferson portraits (copies) 1905 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Thomas Jefferson to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1808 October 27; Photocopy. Original in Thomas Jefferson papers. (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Thomas Jefferson to his fellow citizens n.d. (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Correspondence of James Madison and James Monroe, 1812-1826 (Box-folder 5:9)
    Photocopies. Originals in Madison and Monroe papers.
    1812 June 12 William [Cobbett?] to James Madison
    1801 March 24 payment to Edward Randoloh; 1812 September 27 Asbury Dickins to Monroe [incomplete]; 1826 December 12 Monroe to Thomas Mann Randolph
  - University of Virginia catalog and letter 1834; 1837 (Box-folder 5:10)
- Series IV: Blackburn and Other Related Families
  - Judith B. Alexander Estate 1866 October 24 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Alexander family genealogy 1973-1975 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - John Sinclair Blackburn 1874; 1912 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - John Sinclair Blackburn newsclippings n.d. (Box-folder 6:4)
  - John Sinclair Blackburn story: "Diary of a Guerilla" n.d. (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Richard S. Blackburn (Father of John Sinclair Blackburn) 1812-1890 (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Sue Taylor Blackburn 1863 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Genealogy of Lucky and Buchanan Families n.d. (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Genealogy of Mann Page from William Randolph of Turkey Island n.d. (Box-folder 6:9)
  - Genealogy news clipping about Rolfe and Taylor families 1939 (Box-folder 6:10)
  - Miscellaneous bill of sale Ephrain Ganison to his children 1802 (Box-folder 6:11)
  - Miscellaneous Certificate of Edward Boteler "Beale Benevolence" 1683 January 8 (Box-folder 6:12)
  - Miscellaneous Certificate of Maureen Duvall "Duvalls Range" 1708 (Box-folder 6:13)
  - Miscellaneous Committee charged with Race relations after the war (handwritten report) 1865 June 24 (Box-folder 6:14)
  - Miscellaneous (Rose) Compass n.d. (Box-folder 6:15)
  - Miscellaneous Debt of H.S. Turner n.d. (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Miscellaneous Deed Clem Baden-plot of land 1835 April 30 (Box-folder 6:17)
  - Miscellaneous Deed Aquila Beal 1835 December 16 (Box-folder 6:18)
  - Miscellaneous Deeds John R. M. Burgess to Nathaniel Crawford n.d. (Box-folder 6:19)
  - Miscellaneous deed John W. Gill- surveyor n.d. (Box-folder 6:20)
  - Miscellaneous deed John Thomas - will 1849 August 21 (Box-folder 6:21)
  - Miscellaneous deeds Thomas Tracy 1813 October 26 (Box-folder 6:22)
  - Miscellaneous Indenture John Lentee to David Crawford 1824 April 3 (Box-folder 6:23)
  - Miscellaneous letters 1808-1863 (Box-folder 6:24)
  - Miscellaneous meeting of the Citizens of Clarke County n.d. (Box-folder 6:25)
  - Oversize plat survey and resurvey of Greenwood Park for Nathhaniel Crawford 1798; 1845
  - University of Virginia Students and Confederate soldiers 1861-1865
  - Indenture Francis McCormick and Cyrus McCormick of Frederick County 1825 Oct 31
- Series V: Portraits of the Randolphs of Edgehill
  - Photograph of Dr. Edward Alexander n.d. (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Picture of Anne Cary Bankhead (granddaughter of Thomas Jefferson) n.d. (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Portrait of Martha Jefferson Randolph n.d. (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Portrait of Peter Jefferson n.d. (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Portrait of Thomas Jefferson n.d. (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Portraits of Page Taylor Kirk (great-great-great granddaughter of Thomas Jefferson through her father Stevens Mason Taylor) n.d. (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Portrait of Edwin R. Page n.d. (Box-folder 7:7)
  - Portrait of Jane Nicholas Randolph (daughter of Thomas Jefferson Randolph; great granddaughter of Thomas Jefferson; married to Robert Garlick Hill Kean) n.d. (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Portrait of Martha Jefferson Randolph n.d. (Box-folder 7:9)
  - Portrait of Mrs Thomas Jefferson Randolph of Edgehll (Jane Hollins Nicholas Randolph; wife of Thomas Jefferson Randolph) n.d. (Box-folder 7:10)
  - Portraits of Thomas Jefferson Randolph (grandson of Thomas Jefferson) n.d. (Box-folder 7:11)
  - Portrait of John Charles Randolp Taylor (husband of Pat Randolph who was the daughter of Thomas Jefferson Randolph and great granddaughter of Thomas Jefferson) n.d. (Box-folder 7:12)
  - Portrait of Cornelia (Nely) Jefferson Taylor n.d. (Box-folder 7:13)
  - Portrait of Mary Mann Page Kirk Moyer as a young girl n.d. (Box-folder 7:14)
  - Portrait of Edwin Roger Kirk as a young boy n.d. (Box-folder 7:15)